#### Contact

scottyanthony@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dr-scott-ellis-b96a51ba (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Nurse Executive Servant Leadership Patient Experience

# Languages

**English** 

#### Certifications

Advanced Cardiac Life Support
Registered Nurse
Executive Management Certified
Registered Nurse

# Dr. Scott Ellis

DNP, MBA, BSB, RN, NEA-BC, CENP, CVRN-BC, SSBBP, PM-LPC Houston, Texas

### Summary

Highly skilled Nurse Executive with over 21 years of experience in the healthcare sector. Understands the complexity of healthcare delivery systems and is dedicated to their improvement. Has a broad clinical and nurse executive background and excels at leading a healthcare team. Reports directly to the Chief Nursing Officer. Possesses a Doctor of Nursing Practice in Nurse Executive Leadership and Innovations (DNP) degree during which over 1000 hours of concentrated Senior Executive curricula were achieved with C-Suite Level preceptors/ mentors (CEO, CNO, CFO, and COO). Master of Business Administration (MBA) along with a Bachelor of Science in Nursing (BSN) and a Bachelor of Science in Biology with a Minor in Chemistry (BSB). Nurse Executive Advanced-Board Certified (NEA-BC), Certified in Executive Nursing Practice (CENP), Cardiovascular Registered Nurse- Board Certified (CVRN-BC), Six Sigma Black Belt Professional (SSBBP), Project Management-Lean Process Certified (PM-LPC), Executive Management Certified, and AONE Certificate Program in Healthcare Finance for Nurse Executives.

# Experience

Memorial Hermann Greater Heights Director of Patient Care December 2016 - January 2020 (3 years 2 months) Houston, Texas

260 bed Magnet designated community hospital. Ranked by the US News and World Report as the #5 hospital in the state of Texas and the #3 hospital in the city of Houston.

**Director of Patient** 

Care

Critical Care Services- Intensive Care Unit, Intermediate Care Unit

Cardiovascular Services- Cardiovascular Intensive Care Unit, Cardiac Care Unit

Pulmonary Services- Respiratory Therapy, Outpatient Pulmonary Function Testing

Nurse Leader Liaison for contracted Wound Care

•Leads an ICU of 22 beds, CVICU of 8 beds, IMU of 12 beds, CCU of 23 beds, and a RT Department including an Outpatient PFT Lab. Nurse Leader liaison for contracted wound care team

oTotal Departments Revenue Generating Budget of \$71 Million
Manages a staff of 4 Clinical Managers, 3 Clinical Coordinators, 1 Unit
Coordinator, and approximately 260: Registered Nurses, Patient Care
Technicians, Unit Clerks, Support Specialist, and Respiratory Therapists= 250
FTEs

- •Ensures regulatory compliance for accrediting bodies
- Increased Staff Engagement Scores
- •Helped in the process of receiving National Magnet recognition by the ANCC in 2017
- •Support initiatives to improve patient satisfaction and patient safety
- •Develops annual budgets to meet the needs of the unit, the institution, and the systems fiscal goals
- •Maintains productivity to institutions fiscal goals
- Continues to exceed Length of Stay target goals
- Develops and maintains Policies and Procedures
- •Sits on multiple campus based and system committees
- Process Owner for System Care Redesigns
- •Preceptor to Master of Science in Nursing (MSN) graduate students
- Directed a construction project of the Intensive Care Unit
- •Lead a team along with the Director of Perioperative Services to achieve the first inpatient accreditation for Vascular Center of Excellence by the Surgical Review Corporation in the entire country

Memorial Hermann Greater Heights Interim Director of Patient Care Family Birthing Center September 2017 - August 2018 (1 year)

Houston, Texas, United States

Interim Director of Patient Care Family Birthing Center (concurrent role 09/2017 to 02/2018 and 05/2018 to 08/2018)

Labor and Delivery, NICU, Postpartum, OB ED, Lactation Services, Maternal Fetal Medicine

- Assumed Interim responsibility for the Family Birthing Center for a 6-month period
- Assumed Interim Director role for a 2nd time for a 3-month period
- Lead Labor and Delivery 10 beds, 18 bed Postpartum, NICU 12 Beds, 4 bed OB ED, Lactation, and Maternal Fetal Medicine
- Began the process for Level II NICU Designation
- Facilitated the request for emergency capital to replace monitoring system in the NICU
- Hired Staff filling 24 FTE shortage that was present across all Family Birthing Center Departments

Memorial Hermann Greater Heights Clinical Manager ICU and CVICU September 2016 - December 2016 (4 months) Houston, Texas

Memorial Hermann Greater Heights is a 260 bed Magnet designated community hospital. It is ranked the #5 hospital in the state of Texas and the #3 hospital in the city of Houston.

Clinical Manager (09/2016 to 11/2016 then promoted to Director of Patient Care)

Intensive Care Unit and Cardiovascular Intensive Care Unit

- Lead an Intensive Care Unit of 22 beds and a Cardiovascular Intensive Care Unit of 8 beds.
- Approximately 118 Registered Nurses, Patient Care Technicians, Unit Clerks, and Support Specialist
- Ensures regulatory compliance for accrediting bodies (Joint Commission, Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, and the State and Local Health Department)
- Maintains productivity to institutions fiscal goals
- Hires, Retains, Engages, Maintains Accountability
- Support initiatives to improve patient satisfaction and patient safety
- · Hired and Oriented Staff ridding of all travel and contract labor

#### **ROBINSON MEDICAL**

Agency Registered Nurse July 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 2 months)

Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, United States

Robinson Medical - Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Agency Registered Nurse (07/2015 to 08/2016)

Agency Registered Nurse at Multiple Facilities

HCA Oklahoma University Medical Center Edmond Manager of Critical Care and Telemetry Services September 2015 - July 2016 (11 months)

Edmond, Oklahoma

HCA Oklahoma University Medical Center Edmond – Edmond, Oklahoma 76 bed community hospital. Member of the OU Medicine family.

Manager of Critical Care and Telemetry Services (09/2015 to 07/2016)

- Lead a 12 bed Intensive Care/ Progressive Care Unit along with Telemetry Monitoring Services
- Approximately 30 Registered Nurses, Monitor Technicians and Health Unit Coordinators
- Educates Staff
- · Assumes responsibility for staff competencies and training
- · Ensures patient issues are promptly and correctly addressed
- Support initiatives to improve patient satisfaction and patient safety
- Developed a safe patient handling process for post-operative recovery in the intensive care unit
- Developed a "Code Admit" and a "Code Discharge" process to promote teamwork and increased patient satisfaction with transition of care
- Developed side effect cards to promote communication about medications

HCA Oklahoma University Medical Center Super Flex Registered Nurse/ Relief Charge Nurse August 2014 - July 2015 (1 year)

Oklahoma City, Oklahoma Area

HCA Oklahoma University Medical Center – Oklahoma City, Oklahoma 680 bed, teaching hospital. Oklahoma's only Level One Trauma Center, First JCAHO-accredited primary stroke center in Oklahoma.

Super Flex Registered Nurse/ Relief Charge Nurse (08/2014 to 07/2015)

- Emergency Department, Intensive Care Units (Trauma, Cardiac, Medical, Transplant/ Neurology), Stepdown Units (Trauma, Cardiac, Medical, Neurological/ Orthopedics, Nephrology), Medical Surgical, Telemetry (Trauma, Cardiac, Medical/Surgical, Neurology/Orthopedics)
- Preceptor for new employed nurses and students

Deaconess Hospital
Float Pool Registered Nurse/ Relief Charge Nurse
June 2012 - August 2014 (2 years 3 months)
Page 4 of 6

Deaconess Hospital - Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

273 beds. Accredited by the Commission on Accreditation of Rehabilitation Facilities (CARF).

Float Pool Registered Nurse/ Relief Charge Nurse (06/2012 to 08/2014)

- Intensive Care Unit, Emergency Department, Cardiac Cath Lab, Medical Surgical Floor, Telemetry, Interventional Radiology, Rehabilitation Services, Skilled Nursing Facility
- Preceptor for new employed nurses and students
- Participated in Ethics Committee
- · Rounded with Chief of Medicine

# Oklahoma Heart Hospital Float Pool Registered Nurse

July 2010 - June 2012 (2 years)

Oklahoma Heart Hospital - Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

99 beds. Physician owned Heart Hospital.

Float Pool Registered Nurse (07/2010 to 06/2012)

• Emergency Room, Cardiac Care Unit, Interventional Unit, Post Cardiac Care Unit

#### Mercy Health Center

Critical Care Float Pool Registered Nurse July 2007 - July 2010 (3 years 1 month)

Mercy Health Center - Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

369 beds. Oklahoma's first Magnet Hospital. Accredited by the Commission on Accreditation of Rehabilitation Facilities (CARF).

Critical Care Float Pool Registered Nurse (07/2007 to 07/2010)

- Intensive Care Units (Medical, Surgical, Trauma/ Neurology)
- Participate in Magnet Recertification Process
- Preceptor for new employed nurses and students

HCA Oklahoma University Medical Center Registered Nurse, Nurse Partner, Senior Patient Services Representative

March 2002 - July 2007 (5 years 5 months)

HCA Oklahoma University Medical Center – Oklahoma City, Oklahoma 680 bed, teaching hospital. Oklahoma's only Level One Trauma Center, First JCAHO-accredited primary stroke center in Oklahoma.

Registered Nurse, Nurse Partner, Senior Patient Services Representative (03/2002 to 07/2007)

• Intensive Care Units

University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center Laboratory Assistant October 2000 - March 2002 (1 year 6 months) Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Laboratory Assistant
\*Cell Biology Cancer Research

### Education

Medical University of South Carolina

Doctorate of Nursing Practice Nurse Executive Leadership and
Innovations, Nursing Administration

Oklahoma Christian University
Master of Business Administration (MBA)

Southern Nazarene University Bachelor's degree, Nursing

Oklahoma City University

Bachelor's degree, Biology Minor in Chemistry